<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Penn CS Theory Group on Penn CS Theory Group (Under construction)</title><link>https://penn-cs-theory.github.io/</link><description>Recent content in Penn CS Theory Group on Penn CS Theory Group (Under construction)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://penn-cs-theory.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Theory Seminar: Sepehr Assadi</title><link>https://penn-cs-theory.github.io/post/theory-seminar/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://penn-cs-theory.github.io/post/theory-seminar/</guid><description>We are excited to announce that this week&amp;rsquo;s speaker is Sepehr Assadi. The talk will take place on Friday, 3/3 at 1pm in Levine 307.
Title: An Asymptotically Optimal Algorithm for Maximum Matching in Dynamic Streams
Abstract: We present an algorithm for the maximum matching problem in dynamic (insertion-deletions) streams with asymptotically optimal space complexity: for any n-vertex graph, our algorithm with high probability outputs an α-approximate matching in a single pass using O(n^2/α^3) bits of space.</description></item><item><title>People</title><link>https://penn-cs-theory.github.io/people/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://penn-cs-theory.github.io/people/</guid><description> Faculty Anindya De Boolean function analysis, Computational Complexity, Learning Theory Brett Hemenway Falk Cryptography, Coding Theory, Security Sampath Kannan Algorithms for Big Data, Algorithmic Fairness, Computational Biology, Program Checking Michael Kearns Algorithmic Fairness, Algorithmic Game Theory, Machine Learning Sanjeev Khanna Approximation Algorithms, Combinatorial Optimization, Sublinear Algorithms Tal Rabin Blockchains, Cryptography, Secure Multiparty Computation
Aaron Roth Algorithmic Fairness, Differential Privacy, Machine Learning Rakesh Vohra Mechanism Design, Auction Theory, Pricing Theory, Machine Learning Erik Waingarten Algorithms for Massive Datasets, Property Testing, Distribution Testing Postdocs Very Cool Postdoc A Very Cool Postdoc B Very Cool Postdoc C Students Exceptional Student A Exceptional Student B Exceptional Student C</description></item><item><title>Theory Seminar Schduele</title><link>https://penn-cs-theory.github.io/seminar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://penn-cs-theory.github.io/seminar/</guid><description>Below is a tenative list of speakers for Spring 2023, and we will announce all talks on the theory-group listserv.
1/27: Erik Waingarten
2/10: Yiping Ma
2/17: Vasilis Gkatzelis
2/24: Yahav Bechavod
3/3: Sepehr Assadi
3/10: Huan Li
3/24: Zihan Tan
3/31: Emily Diana
4/7: Rajesh Jayaram
4/14: Xi Chen
4/21: Surbhi Goel
4/28: Sergei Vassilvitskii</description></item></channel></rss>