<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Penn CS Theory Group on Penn CS Theory Group (Under construction)</title><link>https://theory.cis.upenn.edu/</link><description>Recent content in Penn CS Theory Group on Penn CS Theory Group (Under construction)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://theory.cis.upenn.edu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Theory Seminar: Kamesh Munagala</title><link>https://theory.cis.upenn.edu/post/kamesh/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theory.cis.upenn.edu/post/kamesh/</guid><description>This week, to account for visit day, theory seminar will be on Thursday March 16 at noon (instead of Friday at 1PM). It will be held in the PCPSE (Perelman Center for Political Science and Economics), in the Dean’s forum on the second floor.
We are excited to have Kamesh Munagala from Duke speaking. Please find the abstract and bio below.
Abstract: We study the classical Bayesian auction setting with a twist: Between the revenue maximizing seller and the buyers lies an intermediary that is better informed about the buyer values.</description></item><item><title>Theory Seminar: Huan Li</title><link>https://theory.cis.upenn.edu/post/huan/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theory.cis.upenn.edu/post/huan/</guid><description>Our speaker for this week&amp;rsquo;s theory seminar is Huan Li, a PhD student here at Penn. The talk will take place in Levine 307 on Friday 3/10 at 1pm.
Title: On Weighted Graph Sparsification by Linear Sketching
Abstract: A seminal work of [Ahn-Guha-McGregor, PODS'12] showed that one can compute a cut sparsifier of an unweighted undirected graph by taking a near-linear number of linear measurements on the graph. Subsequent works also studied computing other graph sparsifiers using linear sketching, and obtained near-linear upper bounds for spectral sparsifiers [Kapralov-Lee-Musco-Musco-Sidford, FOCS'14] and first non-trivial upper bounds for spanners [Filtser-Kapralov-Nouri, SODA'21].</description></item><item><title>Theory Seminar: Sepehr Assadi</title><link>https://theory.cis.upenn.edu/post/sepehr/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theory.cis.upenn.edu/post/sepehr/</guid><description>We are excited to announce that this week&amp;rsquo;s speaker is Sepehr Assadi. The talk will take place on Friday, 3/3 at 1pm in Levine 307.
Title: An Asymptotically Optimal Algorithm for Maximum Matching in Dynamic Streams
Abstract: We present an algorithm for the maximum matching problem in dynamic (insertion-deletions) streams with asymptotically optimal space complexity: for any n-vertex graph, our algorithm with high probability outputs an α-approximate matching in a single pass using O(n^2/α^3) bits of space.</description></item><item><title>People</title><link>https://theory.cis.upenn.edu/people/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theory.cis.upenn.edu/people/</guid><description> Faculty Anindya De Boolean function analysis, Computational Complexity, Learning Theory Brett Hemenway Falk Cryptography, Coding Theory, Security Sampath Kannan Algorithms for Big Data, Algorithmic Fairness, Computational Biology, Program Checking Michael Kearns Algorithmic Fairness, Algorithmic Game Theory, Machine Learning Sanjeev Khanna Approximation Algorithms, Combinatorial Optimization, Sublinear Algorithms Tal Rabin Blockchains, Cryptography, Secure Multiparty Computation Aaron Roth Algorithmic Fairness, Differential Privacy, Machine Learning Rakesh Vohra Mechanism Design, Auction Theory, Pricing Theory, Machine Learning Erik Waingarten Algorithms for Massive Datasets, Property Testing, Distribution Testing Postdocs Very Cool Postdoc A Very Cool Postdoc B Very Cool Postdoc C Students Exceptional Student A Exceptional Student B Exceptional Student C</description></item><item><title>Theory Seminar Schedule</title><link>https://theory.cis.upenn.edu/seminar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theory.cis.upenn.edu/seminar/</guid><description>Below is a tentative list of speakers for Spring 2023, and we will announce all talks on the theory-group listserv.
1/27: Erik Waingarten
2/10: Yiping Ma
2/17: Vasilis Gkatzelis
2/24: Yahav Bechavod
3/3: Sepehr Assadi
3/10: Huan Li
3/16: Kamesh Munagala
3/24: Zihan Tan
3/31: No Talk
4/7: Rajesh Jayaram
4/14: Xi Chen
4/21: Surbhi Goel
4/28: Sergei Vassilvitskii</description></item></channel></rss>